let set13 =
    [
        {
            question: `#1. Consider the following: \n 1. Cotton \n 2. PET \n 3. Plastic \n Which of the above is/are example(s) of natural polymers?`,
            options:
                [
                    'A. 1 only',
                    'B. 2 only',
                    'C. 1 and 2 only',
                    'D. 1, 2 and 3',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: A`,
            exp: `Explanation: A polymer is made up of may small units. A polymer can be either natural or synthetic. Cotton is a natural polymer, called cellulose. Cellulose comprises of many molecules of glucose monomers. Wool, silk and leather are also examples of natural polymers. Synthetic fibres are obtained from the chemical reaction of petrochemicals. Polyethylene Terephthalate is a synthetic polymer, a common example of polyester. It is used to make bottles, utensils, film, wires, and other essential products. Like synthetic fibres, plastic is also a polymer. Polythene (poly + ethene) is an example of plastic. Plastic takes many years to decompose, hence it is not environment friendly.`
        },
        {
            question: `#2. Match the items of column 1 with column 2 and select the correct answer using the code given below. \n Column 1 Column 2 \n A. Rayon 1. It is made from coal, water and air. \n B. Nylon 2. It is called synthetic silk. \n C. Terylene 3. It is a polyester. \n D. Acrylic 4. It is used to make wool, sweater and shawls.`,
            options:
                [
                    'A. 2 1 3 4',
                    'B. 1 2 4 3',
                    'C. 3 4 1 2',
                    'D. 4 3 2 1',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: A`,
            exp: `Explanation: Rayon, nylon, terylene and acrylic are all examples of synthetic fibres. Rayon is also called synthetic silk. It is made by the synthetic treatment of wood cellulose. It is cheaper than silk. Nylon is synthesised from coal, air and water. It is the first fully synthetic fibre. Nylon wire are more durable than steel wire. Terylene is a popular polyester. Fabric made from this fibre does not get wrinkled easily. Acrylic is used to make wool, sweater, shawl and blankets. Objects made of acrylic are cheaper and their maintenance is easier.`
        },
        {
            question: `#3. Uniforms of firemen have a coating to make them flame resistant. Which of the following is used to make that coat?`,
            options:
                [
                    'A. Melamine',
                    'B. Bekalite',
                    'C. Polyester',
                    'D. Teflon',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: A`,
            exp: `Explanation: Uniforms of firemen have a coating of melamine plastic to make them flame resistant. Melamine is fire-resistant and is more heat resistant as compared to other plastics. Bakelite is a bad conductor of heat and electricity. It is used to make switches, handles of utensils, etc. Polyester is a polymer made up of (poly + ester) monomers. Ester is the chemical responsible for the sweet smell of fruits. Teflon is a special plastic, which does not allow oil or water to stick on it. It is used to make the non-sticky layer on the utensils used to cook food.`
        },
        {
            question: `#4. Which of the following metals remains in liquid state at room temperature?`,
            options:
                [
                    'A. Sodium',
                    'B. Mercury',
                    'C. Potassium',
                    'D. All of the above',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: B`,
            exp: `Explanation: Mercury is the metal that exists as liquid in room temperature. It is an anomalous metal. Sodium and Potassium metals are soft and can be cut with a knife.`
        },
        {
            question: `#5. If copper utensils are exposed to moist air for a long time, they develop a green layer over them. Which of the following is that green substance?`,
            options:
                [
                    'A. Copper Hydroxide',
                    'B. Copper Carbonate',
                    'C. A mixture of (a) and (b)',
                    'D. None of these',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: C`,
            exp: `Explanation: When copper utensils are exposed to moist air for a long time, they develop a green layer over them. This green substance is a mixture of Copper Hydroxide [Cu(OH)2] and Copper Carbonate [CuCO3].`
        },
        {
            question: `#6. Which of the following is a highly reactive metal which catches fire when exposed to air?`,
            options:
                [
                    'A. Phosphorus',
                    'B. Sodium',
                    'C. Iodine',
                    'D. Bromine',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: A`,
            exp: `Explanation: Phosphorus, Iodine and Bromine are all non-metals. They do not generally react with water, but are highly reactive in air. Of the three, phosphorus is the most reactive non-metal. It catches fire on being exposed to air. To prevent the contact of phosphorus with atmospheric oxygen, it is stored in water.Bromine is the only non- metal which exists as a liquid in room temperature. Sodium is a metal which is highly reactive in nature. It reacts rapidly with air and water. A lot of energy is generated in these reactions. Therefore, it is stored in kerosene oil.`
        },
        {
            question: `#7. Name the synthetic polymer that resembles like natural rubber?`,
            options:
                [
                    'A. Polypropene',
                    'B. Neoprene',
                    'C. Nylon',
                    'D. Chloroprene',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: B`,
            exp: `Explanation: Neoprene (CR), also called polychloroprene or chloroprene rubber, synthetic rubber produced by the polymerization (or linking together of single molecules into giant, multiple-unit molecules) of chloroprene. A good general-purpose rubber, neoprene is valued for its high tensile strength, resilience, oil and flame resistance, and resistance to degradation by oxygen and ozone; however, its high cost limits its use to special-properties applications. This polymer tends to crystallize and harden slowly at temperatures below about 10 °C (50 °F). It also crystallizes on stretching, so cured components are strong even without the addition of fillers such as carbon black. Because the double bond between the carbon atoms is shielded by the pendant atoms and CH2 groups, the molecular interlinking necessary for vulcanizing the polymer to a cured rubber is usually effected through the chlorine atom. The presence of chlorine in the molecular structure causes this elastomer to resist swelling by hydrocarbon oils, to have greater resistance to oxidation and ozone attack, and to possess a measure of flame resistance. Principal applications are in products such as wire and cable insulation, hoses, belts, springs, flexible mounts, gaskets, and adhesives, where resistance to oil, heat, flame, and abrasion are required.`
        },
        {
            question: `#8. Name the polymer that can have strong intermolecular forces?`,
            options:
                [
                    'A. Polyester',
                    'B. Teflon',
                    'C. Vinyl Rubber',
                    'D. Polypropene',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: A`,
            exp: `Explanation: Polyester is a generalised term for any fabric or textile, which is made using polyester yarns or fibres. It is a shortened name for a synthetic, man-made polymer, which, as a specific material, is most commonly referred to as a type called polyethylene terephthalate (PET). It is made by mixing ethylene glycol and terephthalic acid. That all sounds extremely scientific, but basically, polyester is a kind of plastic. What are some characteristics of polyester fabric?  Polyester is very durable and is resistant to many chemicals  This is a popular fabric in the fashion industry, as it is resistant to shrining and stretching. It is also resistant to wrinkling and abrasions  The fibres used to create Polyester are very strong yet lightweight  The fibres are easily dyed  It retains its shape very well  Polyester fabric is easy to look after and it can be washed and dried at home  It is a quick drying fabric, so a popular choice for outdoors clothing`
        },
        {
            question: `#9. Aluminium is used for making cooking utensils. Which of the following properties of aluminium are responsible for the same? \n 1. Good thermal conductivity \n 2. Good electrical conductivity \n 3. Ductility \n 4. High melting point`,
            options:
                [
                    'A. 1 and 2',
                    'B. 1 and 3',
                    'C. 2 and 3',
                    'D. 1 and 4',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: D`,
            exp: `Explanation: Some of the most common properties of Aluminium are good thermal conductivity, malleability, light weight and high melting point which make it useful for making cooking utensils.`
        },
        {
            question: `#10. Which of the following represent the correct order of decreasing reactivity?`,
            options:
                [
                    'A. Mg > Al > Zn > Fe',
                    'B. Mg > Zn > Al > Fe',
                    'C. Al > Zn > Fe > Mg',
                    'D. Mg > Fe > Zn > Al',
                ],
            answer: `Answer: A`,
            exp: `Explanation: The decreasing order of the reactivity of the common metals is given below: Li, K, Na, Ba, Ca, Mg , Al, Mn, Zn, Fe, Ni, Sn, Pb, [H], Cu,Hg, Ag, Au,Pt, `
        }
    ]